[-] Good morning,
and welcome to this short breathing exercise.
It's the start of your day,
and before you get pulled into meetings,
your to-do list,
and a multitude of requests from coworkers or family,
let's just take a few minutes to pause together
to come into the present moment and to ground ourselves.
I know it can be hard finding time
in an already packed schedule,
but my hope is that exercises like this one
will actually become part of your day,
instead of something extra you have to fit in.
I would even recommend blocking this time in your calendar
to help you start your workday
with a feeling of calm and clarity.
So take a moment to get comfortable wherever you're sitting.
Nice, upright back with relaxed shoulders.
Make sure both feet are flat on the floor,
and you can just place your hands in your lap,
eyes open with a nice soft, downward gaze.
And just noticing the sensation
of your body pressing down in the seat.
Feeling your feet on the floor
and your hands in your lap.
Notice if your shoulders are tense.
Can you, perhaps, bring them down away from your ears?
We're just using this moment
to come out of the mind and into the body,
fully present in this space.
And you can close your eyes
if you feel comfortable doing so.
We're going to take 10 breaths together.
So first one, start by taking a big, deep breath,
breathing in through your nose
and out through your mouth.
And second, breathing in through your nose
And three, in through your nose
and out through your mouth.
And four.
And five.
And six, in three your nose
and out through your mouth.
And seven.
And eight.
And nine.
And one more deep breath,
in through your nose
and out through your mouth.
And you can allow your breathing just to return to normal,
in and out through the nose.
Open your eyes if you had them closed
and just pausing in this moment,
knowing this time was for you,
fully present and connected ahead of starting your day.
And as you head into your day,
just setting that intention to take this feeling with you.